ALVIN JACKSON

SENIOR UX & UI PRODUCT DESIGNER

Creating harmony between a product, a user, and a business is very essential. I am a strategist that tailors a well documented plan to build a solution for all team members, users, and stake holders. With the challenging ever changing requirements of people, products, and industries I thrive in creating meaningful successful applications.

Experienced in remote work and open to relocate or come in office if needed.

Address:

70 Lost Meadow Trail The Hills, TX 78738

P: 737-206-0715

E: hello@alvinjackson.com W: www.alvinjackson.com

SKILLS & TECH



UI DESIGN

8+ yrs. creating experiences in Invison, Adobe XD & Suites, Basalmiq, Axure, Sketch and Figma.



HTML & CSS

3+ years building responsive using Visual Studio, Github, Bootstrap, Javascript, and more.



LEAD

Working with developers, designers, and stakeholders using Trello, Jira, Zoom, Skype, Slack, and Azure.



UX & RESEARCH

8 + years creating user flows, journeys, and more. Invision, Flowmapp,Overflow, Miro, Mural, and Adobe.



DEVELOP & LAUNCH

Coordinating with dev. team, finalize designs, speed test, micro details, A/B testing, and launch.



EXPERIENCE

10+ YEARS OF CREATING AND LEADING

INVENTIVE WORKS. LLC

Senior UX and UI | 2019 - present

Assist in the creative direction of the user experience and design flow regarding applications interface. My work is a compilation of ux strategies and UI design. Using Jira and Slack ensures strong team communication, as we take concepts to produced design mockups, prototypes, and development to meet aggressive deadlines for enterprise applications.

VESTOR POCKET, LLC

Senior UX & UI | 2017 - 2020 Recent Projects | SA Shoe & Company, Livestock Loader, LLC, DebonaireU

Beginning with research and preplanning I am able to construct a strong data analysis, user stories, and user flows. Exploration and design then take place using wireframes, style guide and mockups. The prototype and design elements are then pushed to the developers where communication is key. Once the product is developed quality testing and launch is accomplished. In some projects, the entire process is not necessary and I am able to modify, update or redesign where needed while working diligently with a team and stake holders.

FIRST UNITED CORP.

Senior UX and UI Product Designer | 2017 - 2018

Through an extensive marketing campaign, I created the user experience and design of websites and multiple landing pages to help bring profitable leads for all investors within the firm. I designed, implemented content, analyzed competitors web pages and websites for A/B testing and generating a good user experience that helped bring profitable leads.

MEDIAFUSION DIGITAL MEDIA PLATFORM

UX and UI | 2016 - 2017

As lead designer I created the user experience and interface of a Netflix style application that could easily be added to their customer's website. This project contract also entailed me creating all marketing and branded materials. Skills and technologies used: HTML, CSS, Basalmiq, Wireframe, Sketch, Invisionapp prototyping, Jira, Adobe Suites.

ALVARA GROUP, LLC

Product Designer & Lead | 2011-2016

As Product Designer & Lead with Alvara Group, I lead many projects consisting of enterprise projects like Hearst Media that needed a in house product that maximized profits and production. The daily work consisted of team collaboration, interviews, research and design. Skills used: Jira, Sketch, Basalmiq, Wireframe, Invisionapp prototyping, HTML, CSS, Content Management Systems, user research and data, Adobe Suites.

EDUCATION

Nielsen Norman Group - UX Conference, 2018

Devry University - BA 2006

